Guide to the New England Council Steel Committee Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
New England Council Steel Committee records
1924-1951
MS 369
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.5
Correspondence and miscellaneous papers of the New England Council Steel Committee, formed to work for the construction of a steel mill in New England. The collection also includes addresses, reports, memoranda, press releases, and printed matter of the New England Council and the New England Steel Development Corporation.
New England Council Steel Committee
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift in 1951 of Frederick S. Blackall, Jr., and of Edward Ingraham; further papers were transferred to this collection from Sterling Memorial Library in 1981.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The New England Council, founded in 1925, is an association of the six New England states (Connecticut, Maine, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, Rhode Island, and Vermont), dedicated to developing and maintaining comprehensive views of economic and social problems and conditions common to the New England states, and to promoting cooperative solutions to these problems. It emphasizes research and the dissemination of information.
In 1947 the Council proposed that a steel mill be built in New England; this collection contains correspondence, memoranda, reports, printed matter, and so forth assembled to promote this project. Included are papers of both the New England Council Steel Committee and the New England Steel Development Corporation, which was set up in 1950 to research and then construct the proposed steel plant. There is also some other general printed matter relating to the New England Council.
The papers were the gift in 1951 of Frederick S. Blackall, Jr., chairman of the New England Council Iron and Steel Supply Committee, and of Edward Ingraham.
Biographical / Historical
The New England Council was founded in 1925 as an association of the six New England states dedicated to developing and maintaining comprehensive views of economic and social problems and conditions common to those states, and to promoting cooperative solutions to these problems.
New England -- Economic policy; New England; New England Council Steel Committee; New England Council; New England Steel Development Corporation
- Inventory
  - Correspondence and miscellaneous papers
    - 1934-1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1948 Nov-1949 Feb
    - 1949 Mar-May (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1949 Jun (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1949 Jul (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1949 Aug (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1949 Sep-Oct (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1949 Nov-Dec (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1950 Jan-Feb (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1950 Mar-Apr (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1950 May-Jun (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1950 Jul-Dec (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1951 Jan-Feb (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1951 Mar-Jun (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - The New England Council
    - Addresses, statements, and reports, 1948-1951 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Agendas and summaries of meetings, 1948-1950 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Memoranda, 1949-1951, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Press releases, 1936, 1949-1951, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Other printed matter and publications, 1924-1947 (Box 2, Folder 17a-d)
  - The New England Steel Development Corporation
    - Report on Prospective market for steel mill products, 1951 January 15 (Box 3, Folder 18-18a)
    - Report on proposed New England steel mill, 1951 April 17
    - Certificate of incorporation [copy], 1950 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Copies of newspaper clippings, 1948-1951 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Magazine articles and reprints, 1948-1950 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous printed matter, 1948-1950, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - "New England Newsletter", 1949 July-1951 April (Box 3, Folder 23)